## **David Simmer**

20 years of deep experience in engineering, design, business, and leadership.

My engineering and design work has been indispensable to a variety of startups, established businesses, non-profits, and educational institutions across the country.

I'm looking for opportunities to work alongside amazing people, orchestrate ideas, and build exciting things.

## Let's talk soon.

david@simmer.ooo https://simmer.ooo

# Experience

### Simmer Inc

## Owner & Creative Developer, 2000-present

Full-stack engineer, designer, project manager, and solo entrepreneur. Orchestrating, designing, prototyping and building clever, good-looking things on the web and IRL. Branding and identity design, responsive design, UX and UI consulting, user-friendly content management creation. Managed subcontractors and my own work with Agile principles. Consistently delivered multiple simultaneous projects on deadline, on budget, and with great attention to detail. Frequently collaborated with other designers & engineers.

#### Rinse

## Lead Software Engineer, Apr 2018-Oct 2019

Engineering, product design, and agile management on a super-sharp team building the future of dry cleaning and laundry service. Successfully led a redesign and redevelopment of the entire frontend within the first month on the job, increasing signups and active customers by more than 100% year over year. Increased operational efficiency by designing, building, and deploying updates to internal tools and mobile apps used by employees in the field. Mentored junior developers, reported directly to CTO. Continually improved our tooling, our architecture, and sought to show off our team's brilliance.

## **Qara Partners**

## Technical Co-founder, Engineering, 2017-2019

Spearheaded the technical parts of selling online products and managed in-house design & technology development for a QA/RA consulting firm in the medical device & digital health space. Full-stack development, branding, product design, and e-commerce. Developing and selling online products for 21 CFR 820 & ISO 13485 efforts.

#### **Nearest You**

## Senior Technical Advisor, 2017

Provided technical and strategic advice to a rapidly-growing online brand locator startup. Architected key components of brand & location analytics. Improved UI/UX and Rails app structure.

## Skills

#### **Engineering leadership**

Product guidance
Business priorities
Project management
Mentoring
Cross-team communication
Architectural decisions
Software development methodologies
Estimation and budgeting
Developer advocacy

#### Full-stack architecture

Python, Django, Postgres, Heroku
APIs, REST, JSON, XML
Microservices
AWS
Ruby on Rails
Javascript, ES6, React, Backbone, Node
Sass, CSS
Webpack, Gulp, Grunt, asset pipelining
HTML, templating languages
Mobile platforms
Cross-browser rendering

#### Design

UX & UI across the device spectrum Interaction Accessibility Motion Prototyping Typography Color



## **Medgineering Inc**

CTO, 2014-2017

Architected, designed, developed, and deployed a quality and regulatory online consultant marketplace called QuickConsult. Built a public MVP, getting us to revenue-positive immediately after launch. Rearchitected v2 on a Rails/Postgres/Dokku stack, laying the groundwork for additional developers to join the team. Familiarized myself with 21 CFR 820 & ISO 13485 to anticipate needs of quality/regulatory clients and consultants. Created and managed branding and communications across our sales and support efforts. Sold the company in 2017.

## **Good Work Group**

Web Development & UX Partner, 2015-present

Full-stack development, design, and technical consulting to assist Good Work Group in making a lasting, positive impact through strategy, creative ideation, storytelling, design, and passion for worthy clients. I led the technical portion of project pitches, helped to land large-budget work, and managed client communication and meetings.

## **Spring**

Web Developer, 2013-2015

Provided high-performance front end development for various high-profile agency clients and brands. Worked remotely in sync with team members across the Atlantic. My very first project with Spring won accolades for its design and technical aspects.

## **Holmes Corporation**

Product Application Developer, 2008-2015

Designer and developer on a small Agile-based software dev team. Designed and built online educational software on a custom Dojo and Python-based framework, working daily with backend developers, project managers, and marketing/sales staff to support and improve learning products with thousands of concurrent users. Kanban, Selenium, Jenkins CI, BDD/TDD. Proposed and completed in-house marketing, design, and ecommerce projects.

## Normandale Community College

Digital Technology Specialist, 1999-2004

Associate webmaster, responsible for new online initiatives, regular website maintenance and upgrades. Advocated for and led a first-of-its-kind in the MnSCU system Section 508 accessibility initiative. Rearchitected and rebuilt the entire college's web platform, developing a complete permissions-enabled CMS (content management system) from scratch, reducing data entry time for academic and marketing departments by 67%. Also provided video production, print design, photography and technology help desk staffing.

## Education

#### Engineering & design

Self-taught (on the shoulders of giants).

It's a rare treat to be a part of a field where the best and brightest among us are eager to share what they know, and where the medium in which we work provides the materials needed to level up.

Over the years I've been doing high-quality work in a variety of production environments long enough to know that learning is never done.

#### Previous career

I was on a science track, focused on human biology and physiology in undergrad. I'd thought that becoming a chiropractor was a smart career choice. It wasn't until after completing grad school and starting a practice that I realized the endemic ethical and scientific problems in that profession.

So I retired my license, sold my practice, and dove headfirst into reinventing my career path. Since then, I've been seeking out ways to use my engineering and design skills in service of the subject that excited me in the first place: how humans actually work.

Let's talk soon.

david@simmer.ooo https://simmer.ooo

